alright number 13 I'm not going to
explain much we have 27 to go I mean 27
total to do we're only halfway through
it you're starting tomorrow evening
number 13 is basically we what was the
guy with the umbrella
somebody tell me now protection from
huge mess-ups Adam goddess in the past
okay
protection from huge boobers you made
when I mean most of my boo-boos I made
when I was 17 I don't know what it is
they were all packed into one year in in
college okay okay that was the umbrella
guy what what meditation was that 11
okay 13 is almost the same okay 13 means
[Music]
bad stuff that's going to happen to you
okay
bad stuff it's going to happen to you
right now in the next few weeks okay
like it didn't come from 20 years ago it
came from last week okay
just steady flow bad crap coming to you
okay from crappy reads last okay
that kind of day-to-day crowd okay
excuse me
but it's a good word that kind of bad
things can't touch you if you're taking
refuge regularly if you under if you're
using just using this less tense it it
gives you your goals but it has a side
effect it infects the rest of your
Karma's even your immediate reversal so
things you did last week don't record
and you just we talked about it in DC I
you know just weird stuff happens to us
we live in this bubble you know somebody
sent a Bentley to pick a song and you
know I was telling Nick Nick somebody
sent a Bentley to pick me up he says
well geshe-la they
program in a different city that night
he says we went in a Rolls Royce I'm
like you know you know right yeah I
didn't get role tonight
yeah saved his life okay
okay so mmm
this one is immediate promise okay
won't mess with you you know subway
breakdowns stuff like that okay like no
just just when you get out of the subway
and stops when you get to the tree Jules
that's like that immediate unhappy
things untouchable means and the word in
Tibetan is untouchable they cannot touch
you
that who's the last people of Buddha met
before he became enlightened yeah demons
what they do they threw scores and they
shot arrows on him because they were
upset they thought he's about to get
enlightened and they're like we gotta
get to the Buddha tree why right now
just go take your arrows pick your
spirits why she's gonna get enlightened
we got a destructive you know and they
ran to the buddha jury i sat there once
it's cool and they put their arrows and
they threw their spears the girls took
off their clothes you know and this year
turned into flowers in the air and the
arrows turned into flowers and they just
come down flower you know and any became
enlightened okay so this is number 13
think about the problems you have I
don't know legal problems tax problems
wife problems you know rent problems job
problems and if you take refuge use of
refuge to deal with your problems and
then it's like armor that the problems
come and they like do you be okay they
just go pumping and they don't touch you
they can't hurt you yes sir Jerome yeah
it helps to yes if you think about the
four powers let's say I lied to people
right so what's what's the actual
antidote what's the third of the four
powers huh make a promise not to do it
again okay and what's the fourth do the
opposite you see number 3 is a negative
promise I won't do it again number 4 is
a positive promise I promise to do the
opposite for a while I'll tell absolute
truth to everybody I don't like your
dress today not the whole truth okay but
if you think about it that's the same as
doing you if you do the four steps it's
the same as the four powers that's the
point okay it's the same you know we
struggle with that in DC I you know do
we tell them the four powers oh we're
just telling the four steps again I
don't make enough money do we tell them
use the four powers to remove your
negative seeds or do we tell them share
things with other people the positive
one is more fits people most people
prefer to share things with others to
fix their poverty then to do themselves
up for six weeks about how cheap they
were got it so when you're teaching
people you can teach them the four
powers which we do but that's emphasis
is negative you know you're a bad person
you collected bad seeds you're poor you
don't have enough money it's
cause you were mean to other people go
go home and confess okay or you know now
what you have anything you get please
share it with other people and then that
that also acts to purify because it's
step number four its power number four
yes but the one that creates a new good
seed also stops the old bad seeds of
ripening that's what we talked about
this morning you see so you killed you
feed to fish with one word no that's not
vegetarian okay okay so we're finished
number thirteen